Guide to the Samuel L. Clemens Papers, 1796-1984 (bulk 1853-1909)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Series B. Samuel L. Clemens Correspondence To Family Members
  - "Dear Charley…" Elmira- Friday, 9 Sep 1887 (10.17 [B.596])
  - "Dear C.L.W and Co…" Hartford, 19 Oct 1887 (10.18 [B.597])
  - "Dear C.L.W and Co…" Hartford, 28 Oct 1887 (10.19 [B.598])
  - "We vote as follows upon the preposition to publish a volume of the sermons of the Rev. Nathaniel J. Burton at half-profits…", 28 Oct 1887 (10.20 [B.599])
  - "Dear C.L.W and Co…", 13 Nov 1887 (10.21 [B.600])
  - "Dear C.L.W and Co…" Hartford, Nov.15, 1887 (10.22 [B.601])
  - "Dear Orion…" Hartford, 8 Dec 1887 (10.23 [B.602])
  - "Dear C.L.W and Co…", 24 Dec 1887 (10.24 [B.603])
  - "Dear Charley…" Hartford, 28 Dec 1887 (10.25 [B.604])
  - "Dear Pamela…" Elmira, 15 Sep 1888 (10.26 [B.605])
  - "Dear Orion…" Elmira, 16 Sep 1888 (10.27 [B.606])
  - "Dear Orion…" Hartford, 3 Oct 1888 (10.28 [B.607])
  - "Dear Orion…" Hartford, 23 Nov 1888 (10.29 [B.608])
  - S.L. Clemens signature, 1889 (10.30 [B.609])
  - "Dear Pamela…" Hartford-Lette r from Olivia L. Clemens, 27 Jan 1889 (10.31 [B.610])
  - "Dear Pamela…" Hartford, 9 Oct 1889 (10.32 [B.611])
  - "Dear Sister…" Hartford, 13 May 1890 (10.33 [B.612])
  - Hartford, Conn.- (On the death of Charles L. Webster, 26 Apr 1891) (10.34 [B.613])
  - "Dear Pamela…" Hartford, 3 June 1891 (10.35 [B.614])
  - "Dear Pamela…" Mentone, 21 Mar 1892 (10.36 [B.615])
  - "Dear Mollie and Orion…" Chicago- 3:15 pm, 24 Apr 1893 (10.37 [B.616])
  - "Dear Pamela and Annie..." Charles L. Webster and Co. Publishers, 675 Fifth Ave., NYC, 21 Sep 1893 (10.38 [B.617])
  - "Dear Annie…" 169 rue de l' Universite, Paris, 28 Nov 1894 (10.39 [B.618])
  - "Dear Pamela…"Villa Viviani, Florence, 5 Feb 1895 (10.40 [B.619])
  - Canadian-Australian SS Line Near the Equator- Letter from Olivia L. L Clemens to her step-sister Sue, 5 Sep 1895 (10.41 [B.620])
  - "Dear Sister…" London, 28 Mar 1897 (10.42 [B.621])
  - "Dear Mrs. Trask…" Trask-Vassar letter, Copy of in SLCs secretary's handwriting, 20 Dec 1901 (10.43 [B.622])
  - Acknowledgement of letter rec'd en occasion of Livy's death, 1904 (10.44 [B.623])
  - "Dear Miss Lyon…" The Grosvenor, NYC, 7 Oct 1904 (10.45 [B.624])
  - Invitation to Mr. Clemens 70th birthday party, 1905 (10.46 [B.624A])
  - "Dear Miss. Lyon…" 21 Fifth Ave. - 10am, 16 July 1906 (10.46 [B.625])
  - The Connecticut Magazine. Marginal notes and underlining in SLC's hand; note by Miss Lyon, 1906 (10.48 [B.626])
  - Miss Francis Munnelly, Hotel Waldorf, 1907 (10.49 [B.627])
  - J. Bigalow Paine, Redding, CT, 1908 (10.50 [B.628])
  - Redding, Conn.- Telegram to Annie Moffett Webster, 55 W 10 St, NYC, 25 Dec 1909 (10.51 [B.629])
- Series C. Correspondence To Samuel L. Clemens and Related Letters
  - Robert G. Ingersoll, Washington, D.C., 11 Dec 1874 (10.52 [C.1])
  - Clara L. Kellogg, Harhurst, Hudson River, 3 Aug 1875 (10.53 [C.2])
  - P.T. Barnum, Bridgeport, CT, 29 Nov 1876 (10.54 [C.3])
  - "Honorable Sir…" Enclosure with P.T. Barnum letter, Worcester, 26 Nov 1876 (10.55 [C.4])
  - Robert Ingersoll, Buffalo, NY, 18 Jan 1880 (10.56 [C.5])
  - E. Booth, Hotel Brunswick, 3 June 1880 (10.57 [C.6])
  - H.B. Mathers (author of "Coming Thru the Rye"), 28 July 1880 (10.58 [C.7])
  - J.B. Aldrich, Ponkapog, MA, 18 Dec 1880 (10.59 [C.8])
  - A. Wing, Washington, D.C., 22 Dec 1880 (10.60 [C.9])
  - E.C. Stedman, 71 W. 54 ST., NY, 12 Jan 1882 (10.61 [C.10])
  - G.W. Cable, Editorial Dept., Century Magazine, 14 Oct 1882 (10.62 [C.11])
  - James Ahern, Hartford, 11 Nov 1882 (10.63 [C.12])
  - Julian Hawthorne, 11 Dec 1882 (10.64 [C.13])
  - Stewart L. Woodford, USA Attorney's Office, NY, 15 Dec 1882 (10.65 [C.14])
  - Edman C. Stedman, 71 W. 54 St., NY, 26 Jan 1883 (10.66 [C.15])
  - J.B. Aldrich, The Atlantic Monthly, Boston, 19 Mar 1883 (10.67 [C.16])
  - Georg Waring, Jr., Newport, 7 Apr 1883 (10.68 [C.17])
  - Jos. R. Hawley, Monday morning, 28 May 1883 (10.69 [C.18])
  - Lother (?), Government House, Ottawa, 26 June 1883 (10.70 [C.19])
  - C.A. Dana, The Sun, NYC, 1 Nov 1883 (10.71 [C.20])
  - W.J. Florence, Route of the Florence's Season 1883-1884, McVickers Theatre, Chicago, 21 Dec 1883 (10.72 [C.21])
  - J.R. Osgood, James R. Osgood Co., Publishers, 4 Feb 1884 (10.73 [C.22])
  - Augustus Daly, Daly's Theatre, Manager's Officer, 27 Feb 1884 (10.74 [C.23])
  - J.R. Osgood, Boston, 26 Mar 1884 (11.1 [C.24])
  - Mr. Howell's writing on envelope: S.L. Clemens, Esq., Riverdale on Hudson, NY, 1884 (11.2 [C.25])
  - W.D. Howells, Boston, 28 Mar 1884 (11.3 [C.26])
  - J. Raymond letter to W.D. Howells, 28 Mar 1884 (11.4 [C.27])
  - W.D. Howells, 4 Louisburg Square, Boston, 29 Mar 1884 (11.5 [C.28])
  - R.M. Raymond, NY, 31 Mar 1884 (11.6 [C.29])
  - W.D.Howells, Boston, 4 Apr 1884 (11.7 [C.30])
  - W.D. Howells, 302 Beacon St., Boston, 28 Feb 1885 (11.8 [C.31])
  - W.D. Howells, Boston, 11 Mar 1885 (11.9 [C.32])
  - Clemma Bradley (nee Lampton), McKinney, TX, 25 Apr 1885 (11.10 [C.33])
  - W.D. Howells, Auburndale, 11 Dec 1885 (11.11 [C.34])
  - W.L. Alden, Consulate General of the United States, Rome, 12 May 1887 (11.12 [C.35])
  - Postcard: Eve: Now own up Adam!, SLC note: Curious old medieval print from the collection of the Vatican, undated (11.13 [C.36])
  - W.D. Howells, Lake George P.O., NY, 21 Aug 1889, 2 Sep 1887 (11.14 [C.37])
  - Josh Billings, The Windsor Hotel, NYC, undated (11.15 [C.38])
  - Clipping: "Twain's Attack on the Czar,", undated (11.16 [C.39])
  - Clipping: Harpers article about Jews, 1898 (11.16 [C.39])
  - Clipping: NY Tribune, "A case in which the Scripture is not fulfilled!", 1 Aug 1900 (11.16 [C.39])
  - Gordon R. Woodward, Lockport, NY, 1902 (11.17 [C.40])
  - Mrs. Tabitha Greening, Palmyra, MO, 19 Nov 1904 (11.18 [C.41])
  - Lawrence Barrett, Philadelphia, Thursday, undated (11.19 [C.42])
  - "My Dear Mr. Rogers…" 323 Fourth Ave., Pittsburgh, PA, 1 Dec 1905 (11.20 [C.43])
  - "Mr. Richard Grant White requests the pleasure of you company…"330 E. 17 St., Stuyvesant Square, undated (11.21 [C.44])
  - "To meet Members of the Savage Club…", 29 June 1905 (11.22 [C.45])
  - "Florence Wyman invites you to a view of her work in pencil…", undated (11.23 [C.46])
  - Clipping: "A Tragedy of To-day,", 1905 (11.24 [C.47])
  - IVL note: Mr. Clemens read this aloud to me this morning, undated (11.24 [C.47])
  - Cartoon by Webster: "The Tramp Printer: Know Mark Twain? You bet I did,", undated (11.25 [C.48])
  - "The author tells how he filled Cooper Union…" NY Times, 1906 (11.26 [C.49])
  - Clipping: Mark Twain on Phonetic Spelling, undated (11.27 [C.50])
  - SLC note, 12 Apr 1906 (11.27 [C.50])
  - Photostat: The House that Twain Built, undated (11.28 [C.51])
  - Dolly Cain, Aurora, Esmeralda County, NV, undated (11.29 [C.52])
  - Oren Root, Jr., NY, 9 May 1906 (11.30 [C.53])
  - J.M. Doubleday, Doubleday Page and Co., 7 Aug 1906 (11.31 [C.54])
  - Augusta M.D. Ogden, Ar-y-Bryn, Tuxedo Park, July 1908 (11.32 [C.55])
  - Prefatory remark. Note. Huckleberry Finn is not an imaginary person, undated (11.33 [C.56])
  - John Watson Cary, Society of Colonial Wars in New York State, 4 Sep 1906 (11.34 [C.57])
  - H.D. McDonald, Lawyer, Paris, TX, 16 Oct 1907 (11.35 [C.58])
  - Mr. and Mrs. Nicholas Murray Butler's card, undated (11.36 [C.59])
  - Mr. John Pyne's card, 9 Dec 1905 (11.37 [C.60])
  - "Letter from unidentified correspondent." Mr. Clemens- Audience waiting for you, undated (11.38 [C.61])
  - Clippings: The Story of the Knickerbocker Trust Co; picture of Mark Twain; and Mark Twain Now After Compliments, (NY Times, undated (11.39 [C.62])
  - 2 letters from Laura Dake, San Diego, 12 Feb 1907 and 16 Feb 1907 (11.40 [C.63])
  - IVL notes dated re Laura Wright Dake, 20 Feb 1906 (11.40 [C.63])
  - Telegram from Lady Warwick, Tuxedo Park, 15 Oct 1907 (11.41 [C.64])
  - Enveloped addressed to Dr. S. Langhorne Clemens, Boston, forward to Mark Twain, 5th Ave. and 9th, NYC, 4 June 1908 (11.42 [C.65])
  - John B. Downing, Daytona, FL, 21 Feb 1907 (11.43 [C.66])
  - Geo. J. Curry, Sharon, WI, 18 Mar 1908 (11.44 [C.67])
  - "My Dear Miss Lyon…" Plainfield, NJ, 30 Apr 1908 (11.45 [C.68])
  - "Dear Cousin…" Cousin Puss, Palmyra, June 1908 (11.46 [C.69])
  - Letter from unidentified correspondent, Hannibal, MO, Feb 1909 (11.47 [C.70])
  - Postcard of Hank Monk's Tombstone, A.H.M., Carson City, NV, undated (11.48 [C.71])
  - Bernard DeVoto, Cambridge, MA, 9 Oct 1941 (11.49 [C.72])
  - Mrs. Lewis, 285 Pleasant St., Pasadena, CA, 15 Nov 1944 (11.50 [C.73])
  - Letter to Herb Stoeckel - Harper and Bros., 27 June 1945 (11.51 [C.74])
  - Leon S. Kaiser, Principal, Mark Twain Junior High School, 8 Sep 1948 (11.52 [C.75])
  - Clipping: "University Gets Mark Twain Items," NY Times, 19 Sep 1954 (11.53 [C.75A])
  - Connor notes, undated (11.54 [C.76A])
  - Mrs. S.C. Webster, 205 W. 57 St., NYC, 14 Oct 1956 (11.55 [C.76])
  - Henry Nash Smith, Univ. of California, 7 Mar 1958 (11.56 [C.77])
  - Mrs. S.C. Webster, The Osborne, 205 W. 57 St., NYC, 10 Mar 1958 (11.57 [C.78])
  - 2 letters, Henry Nash Smith, Univ. of California, 18 Apr 1958 (11.58 [C.79])
  - Henry Nash Smith, Univ. of California, 12 Oct 1962 (11.59 [C.80])
  - Witter and Harpole Law Offices, Los Angeles, 5 Aug 1966 (11.60 [C.81])
  - Myron E. Harpole, Los Angeles, Aug.22, 1966 (11.61 [C.82])
  - Geo. E. Dutton, Jr. Trust officer, Bank of Delaware, 10 July 1967 (11.62 [C.83])
  - H.S. Tuthill, Cummings and Lockwood, Stamford, CT, 17 July 1967 (11.63 [C.84])
  - Geo. E. Dutton, Wilmington, DE, 20 July 1967 (11.64 [C.85])
  - Fredrick Anderson, Editor, Mark Twain Papers, Univ. of California, 10 Apr 1968 (11.65 [C.86])
  - Henry Nash Smith, Univ. of California, 28 June 1968 (11.66 [C.87])
  - "Dear Mr. Connor…" Works of Mark Twain, Iowa - California edition, Berkeley, CA, 5 Aug 1971 (11.67 [C.88])
  - "Dear Mr. Connor…" Northeast Missouri State University, Kirksville, MO, 27 Mar 1973 (11.68 [C.89])
  - Thomas G. Chamberlain, Attorney for Mark Twain Trust, NY, 25 Oct 1974 (11.69 [C.90])
  - Fredrick Anderson, Editor, Mark Twain Papers, Univ. of California, 4 Mar 1975 (11.70 [C.91])
  - Dixon Wecter, Hungtington, 26 Sep 1947 (11.71 [C.92])
  - 2 clippings: "I keep coming back…"(re: Mark Twain and Hawaii - and a letter by Fredrick Anderson in NY Review of Books, 20 Mar 1975 (11.72 [C.93])
- Series D. Olivia Langdon Clemens Correspondence to Family Members
  - Dear Sam, 17 Sep 1901 (12.1 [D.14])
  - Dear Sam, 23 Jan 1902 (12.2 [D.15])
  - "Dear Charley - Will you please…", undated (12.3 [D.16])
  - "Dear Charley - I want to trouble you…", undated (12.4 [D.17])
  - "Dear Charley - Mr. Clemens is in Boston,", undated (12.5 [D.18])
  - Note by miss Lyon: "I saw Mr. Clemens twice in Riverdale,", 1903 (12.6 [D.19])
  - Letter to Will Clemens, 16 Feb 1902 (12.7 [D.20])
  - Notes dated and in handwriting of Miss Lyon re: "What is a Man?", 7 May 1933 (12.8 [D.21])
  - Mark Twain's Tribute to Livy, undated (12.9 [D.22])
- Series E. Clara Clemens Correspondence To Family
  - "Dear Aunt Pamela…" Hartford, 30 Dec, 1884 (12.10 [E.1])
  - "Dear Aunt Pamela…" Calcutta, India, 18 Feb 1896 (12.11 [E.2])
  - Saturday, 17 Livingston Place, Letter to Miss Lyon from NYC, undated (12.12 [E.3])
  - Letter to Miss Lyon from Germany, 4 Aug 1908 (12.13 [E.4])
  - Miss Isabel Lyon, Princess Hotel, Hamilton, Bermuda, 24 Mar 1908 (12.14 [E.5])
  - "My Dear Cousin Annie…" Stormfield, Redding, CT, 13 May 1910 (12.15 [E.6])
  - "Dear Cousin Annie…" Stormfield, Redding, CT, 30 May 1910 (12.16 [E.7])
  - "Dear Cousin Annie…" Munich, 14 Feb 1914 (12.17 [E.8])
  - "Thank you my dear cousin…", 1936 (12.18 [E.9])
  - "My dear Cousin Jean…" La Jolla, CA, 18 Jan 1954 (12.19 [E.10])
  - 10 sheets of clippings, undated (12.20 [E.11])
- Series F. Jean L. Clemens Correspondence to Family
  - Letter to Miss Lyon, 162 Upper Mountain Ave., Montclair, NJ, 14 Mar 1909 (12.21 [F.1])
  - S.L. Clemens, Stormfield, 25 Dec 1910 (12.22 [F.2])
  - IVL's note re: Jean Clemens, undated (12.23 [F.3])
  - IVL's notes for Me. How re Jean Clemens, undated (12.24 [F.4])
- Series G. Susan Clemens
  - In memoriam Olivia Susan Clemens, 18 Aug 1897 (12.25 [G.1])
- Series H. Mark Twain Birthday Celebrations
  - Harpers Weekly, ed. By George Harvey, 23 Dec 1905 (12.26 [H.1])
  - Mark Twain's 70th Birthday - Souvenir of Its Celebration, Supplement to Harpers, 23 Dec 1905 (12.27 [H.2])
  - Calendar of Pleiades Club, 22 Dec 1907 (12.28 [H.3])
  - Publishers' Weekly, 7 Oct 1905 (12.29 [H.4])
  - Clippings re 70th birthday, undated (12.30 [H.5])
  - Calendar of American Academy of Arts and Letters and The National Institute of Arts and Letters, 14 Nov 1935 (12.31 [H.6])
- Series I. Samuel Langhorne Clemens' Funeral
  - Calendar of Memorial Ceremonies, 30 Nov 1910 (12.32 [I.1])
  - Harpers Weekly, 17 Dec 1910 (12.33 [I.2])
  - Clippings, undated (12.34 [I.3])
- Series J. Mark Twain's Homes
  - Florida, Missouri, undated; (3 brochures) (12.35 [J.1])
  - Hannibal, Missouri, undated; (photo, 3 Brochures, 3 sheets of clippings) (12.36 [J.2])
  - Farmington Ave., Hartford, Connecticut, undated; (3 brochures, 1 magazine article, 1 newspaper clipping, 1 map) (12.37 [J.3])
  - Stormfield, Redding, Connecticut, undated; (picture, clippings, Mark Twain Library Bulletin) (12.38 [J.4])
- Series K. Mark Twain Clippings
  - sheets and clippings #2-20, undated; (originals) (13.1 [K.1,K.2])
  - sheets and clippings #21-50, undated; (originals) (13.2 [K.1,K.2])
  - sheets and clippings #51-75, undated; (originals) (13.3 [K.1,K.2])
  - sheets and clippings # 76-100, undated; (originals) (13.4 [K.1,K.2])
  - sheets and clippings #101-121, undated; (originals) (13.5 [K.1,K.2])
  - Sale catalogue and manuscripts of S.L. Clemens, Part I, 7-8 Feb 1911 (13.6 [K.3])
  - 1950 article by Edgar M. Branch, Thematic Form in Huck Finn (13.7 [K.4])
  - 1952 article by Fred W. Lorch, Mark Twain's "Artemus Ward" Lecture (13.8 [K.5])
  - 1957 article by Henry Nash Smith, The Structure of Roughing It (13.9 [K.6])
  - Oversized clippings, (microfilmed?) (Box 37)
- Series L. Mississippi Life
  - Card of the Mississippi and Ohio Rivers Pilot Society, undated (14.1 [L.1])
  - Photograph of SS Baton Rouge of the New Orleans Anchor Line, with note from Dixon Wecter, undated (14.2 [L.2])
  - Photograph of SS Mark Twain, City of Saint Louis Harbor Department, undated (14.3 [L.3])
  - Reprint by Currier and Ives of steamboat race, NY Times, 12 Oct 1930 (14.4 [L.4])
  - Clipping: View of a Mississippi steamboat center salon, undated (14.5 [L.5])
  - Peter Schrag article, "Life on the Mississippi," Saturday Review, 12 Dec 1970 (14.6 [L.6])
- Series M. Copies of Mark Twain Publications
  - S.L. Clemens letter written in answer to inquiries made by a personal friend..., undated (14.7 [M.1])
  - S.L. Clemens letter written to a personal friend, undated (14.8 [M.2])
  - "William Dean Howells" article by Twain in Harpers Monthly Magazine, and clipping of a review, July 1906 (14.9 [M.3])
  - "A Horse's Tale, A Story in Two Parts" by Twain in Harpers Monthly Magazine, Aug and Sep 1906 (14.10 [M.4])
  - 4 Howard Pyle illustrations of St. Joan of Arc in Harpers Monthly Magazine, undated (14.11 [M.5])
  - "Letters from the Earth"and interview with daughter Clara in Look Magazine, 1962 (14.12 [M.6])
  - "Here Comes Mark Twain" – a review of Readers Digest movie, undated (14.13 [M.7])
  - American Heritage advertisement, undated (14.14 [M.8])
- Series N. The Mentor Magazine
  - Mark Twain Number - articles by his biographer and close friends, May 1924 (14.15 [N.1])
- Series O. Mark Twain Society's Publications
  - Mark Twain Quarterly, 1937, 1942-1943; (2 issues) (14.16 [O.1])
  - The Twainian, 1949-1977; (52 issues and 3 portions - folder 1 of 2) (14.17 [O.2])
  - The Twainian, 1949-1977; (52 issues and 3 portions - folder 2 of 2) (14.18 [O.2])
  - The Twainian, undated; (Ephemera) (14.19 [O.2])
- Series P. Materials Related to Huckleberry Finn
  - Cut Proofs of Kemble Illustrations
    - p.283 Who do You Reckon It Is? (15.1 [P.B.1])
    - Franklin J. Meine, Some Notes on the First Edition of "Huck Finn" (15.2 [P.B.2])
    - Frontispiece (15.3 [P.B.3])
    - p.17 Chapter I. (The Widow's) (15.4 [P.B.3])
    - p.19 Miss Watson (15.4 [P.B.3])
    - p.21 Huck Stealing Away (15.4 [P.B.3])
    - p.22 Chapter II (The Tip-Toed Along) (15.5 [P.B.3])
    - p.24 Jim (15.5 [P.B.3])
    - p.25 Tom Sawyer's Band of Robbers (15.5 [P.B.3])
    - p.29 Chapter III (Miss Watson's Lecture) (15.6 [P.B.3])
    - p.31 The Robbers Dispersed (15.6 [P.B.3])
    - p.34 Chapter IV (!!!!!) (15.7 [P.B.3])
    - p.36 Judge Thatcher Surprised (15.7 [P.B.3])
    - p.37 Jim Listening (15.7 [P.B.3])
    - p.39 Chapter V ("Pap") (15.8 [P.B.3])
    - p.41 Huck and His Father (15.8 [P.B.3])
    - p.43 Reforming the Drunkard (15.9 [P.B.3])
    - p.44 Falling from Grace (15.9 [P.B.3])
    - p.45 Chapter VI (Getting Out of the Way) (15.10 [P.B.3])
    - p.48 Thinking It Over (15.10 [P.B.3])
    - p.53 Chapter VII ("Git Up") (15.11 [P.B.3])
    - p.54 The Shanty (15.11 [P.B.3])
    - p.56 Shooting the Pig (15.12 [P.B.3])
    - p.59 Taking a Rest (15.12 [P.B.3])
    - p.63 Watching the Boat (15.12 [P.B.3])
    - p.64 Discovering the Camp Fire (15.12 [P.B.3])
    - p.67 Jim and the Ghost (15.13 [P.B.3])
    - p.72 Misto Bradish's Nigger (15.13 [P.B.3])
    - p.74 Chapter IX (Exploring the Cave) (15.14 [P.B.3])
    - p.79 Chapter X (They Found Eight Dollars) (15.15 [P.B.3])
    - p.80 Jim and the Snake (15.15 [P.B.3])
    - p.81 Old Hank Bunker (15.16 [P.B.3])
    - p.82 "A Fair Fit" (15.16 [P.B.3])
    - p.84 Chapter XI ("Come In") (15.17 [P.B.3])
    - p.87 "Him and Another Man" (15.17 [P.B.3])
    - p.90 She Puts up a Snack (15.18 [P.B.3])
    - p.91 "Hump Yourself" (15.18 [P.B.3])
    - p.98 Chapter XII ("Please Don't, Bill") (15.19 [P.B.3])
    - p.100 "It Ain't Good Morals" (15.19 [P.B.3])
    - p.102 Chapter XIII (In a Fix) (15.20 [P.B.3])
    - p.109 Chapter XIV (Turning Over the Truck) (15.20 [P.B.3])
    - p.104 Chapter XIII ("Hello, What's Up?") (15.21 [P.B.3])
    - p.112 Chapter XIV (The Story of "Sollerman") (15.21 [P.B.3])
    - p.110 Solomon and His Million Wives (15.22 [P.B.3])
    - p.117 Chapter XV (Along the Snags) (15.22 [P.B.3])
    - p.118 Asleep on the Raft (15.23 [P.B.3])
    - p.126 Chapter XVI ("Boy, That's a Lie") (15.23 [P.B.3])
    - p.127 "Here I Is, Huck" (15.24 [P.B.3])
    - p.131 Climbing Up the Bank (15.24 [P.B.3])
    - p.132 Chapter XVII ("Who's There?") (15.25 [P.B.3])
    - p.134 "Buck" (15.25 [P.B.3])
    - p.138 "It Made Her Look Spidery" (15.26 [P.B.3])
    - p. 40 "They Got Him Out and Emptied Him" (15.26 [P.B.3])
    - p.142 The House (15.27 [P.B.3])
    - p.143 Chapter XVIII (Col. Grangerford) (15.27 [P.B.3])
    - p.149 "And Asked Me If I Liked Her" (15.28 [P.B.3])
    - p.153 "Behind the Wood-Pile" (15.29 [P.B.3])
    - p.108 Chapter XIII (We Turned In and Slept) (15.29 [P.B.3])
    - p.157 Chapter XIX (Hiding Day-Times) (15.30 [P.B.3])
    - p.115 Chapter XV ("We Would Sell the Raft") (15.30 [P.B.3])
    - p.160 Chapter XIX ("And Dogs A-Coming") (15.31 [P.B.3])
    - p.170 Chapter XX (The King As Juliet) (15.31 [P.B.3])
    - p.163 Chapter XIX ("By Rights I Am a Duke!") (15.32 [P.B.3])
    - p.165 "I Am the Late Dauphin" (15.32 [P.B.3])
    - p.166 "Tail Piece" (15.33 [P.B.3])
    - p.167 Chapter XX (On the Raft) (15.34 [P.B.3])
    - p.122 Chapter XVI ("It Amounted to Something Being A Raftsman") (15.34 [P.B.3])
    - p.174 Chapter XX ("A Pirate for Thirty Years") (15.35 [P.B.3])
    - p.177 Chapter XXI (Practicing) (15.36 [P.B.3])
    - p.196 Chapter XXIII (Tragedy) (15.36 [P.B.3])
    - p.182 Chapter XXI ("Gimme A Chaw") (15.37 [P.B.3])
    - p.226 Chapter XXVI (The Duke Looks Under the Bed) (15.37 [P.B.3])
    - p.185 Chapter XXI (A Little Monthly Drunk) (15.38 [P.B.3])
    - p.215 Chapter XXV (Making Up the "Deffisit") (15.38 [P.B.3])
    - p.187 Chapter XXI (The Death of Boggs) (15.39 [P.B.3])
    - p.235 Chapter XXVII ("Was You In My Room?) (15.39 [P.B.3])
    - p.189 Chapter XXII (Sherburn Steps Out) (15.40 [P.B.3])
    - p.211 Chapter XXV ("You Bet It Is") (15.40 [P.B.3])
    - p.191 Chapter XXII (A Dead Head) (15.41 [P.B.3])
    - p.200 Chapter XXIII ("Henry the Eighth in Boston Harbor") (15.41 [P.B.3])
    - p.216 Chapter XXV (Going for Him) (15.41 [P.B.3])
    - p.237 Chapter XXVII (Jawing) (15.41 [P.B.3])
    - p.193 Chapter XXII (He Shed Seventeen Suits) (15.42 [P.B.3])
    - p.218 (The Doctor) (15.42 [P.B.3])
    - p.203 Chapter XXIV (Harmless) (15.43 [P.B.3])
    - p.220 Chapter XXVI (The Cubby) (15.43 [P.B.3])
    - p.205 Chapter XXIV (Adolphus) (15.44 [P.B.3])
    - p.101 Chapter XII ("Oh! Lordy Lordy!") (15.44 [P.B.3])
    - p.207 Chapter XXIV (He Fairly Empties That Young Fellow) (15.45 [P.B.3])
    - p.248 Chapter XXVIII (The Auction) (15.45 [P.B.3])
    - p.209 Chapter XXIV (Alas, Our Poor Brother) (15.46 [P.B.3])
    - p.212 Chapter XXV (Leaking) (15.46 [P.B.3])
    - p.233 Chapter XXVII (He Had a Rat!) (15.46 [P.B.3])
    - p.219 Chapter XXV (The Bag of Money) (15.47 [P.B.3])
    - p.224 Chapter XXVI ("Honest Injun") (15.47 [P.B.3])
    - p.299 Huck Takes the Money (15.47 [P.B.3])
    - p.230 Chapter XXVII (A Crack in the Dining-Room Door) (15.48 [P.B.3])
    - p.239 Chapter XXVIII (In Trouble) (15.48 [P.B.3])
    - p.221 Chapter XXVI (Supper With the Hare-Lip) (15.49 [P.B.3])
    - p.232 Chapter XXVII (The Undertaker) (15.49 [P.B.3])
    - p.198 Chapter XXIII (Their Pockets Bulged) (15.50 [P.B.3])
    - p.241 Chapter XXVIII (Indignation) (15.50 [P.B.3])
    - p.242 How to Find Them (15.50 [P.B.3])
    - p.244 He Wrote (15.50 [P.B.3])
    - p.355 Chapter XLII (Tom Sawyer Wounded) (15.51 [P.B.3])
    - p.355 Chapter XLII (Tom Sawyer Wounded) (15.51 [P.B.3])
    - p.252 Chapter XXIX (The Doctor Leads Huck) (15.52 [P.B.3])
    - p.269 Chapter XXXI ("Who Nailed Him?") (15.52 [P.B.3])
    - p.255 Chapter XIX (The Duke Wrote) (15.53 [P.B.3])
    - p.331 Chapter XXXVIII (Irrigation) (15.53 [P.B.3])
    - p.257 Chapter XXIX ("Gentlemen-Gentlemen!") (15.53 [P.B.3])
    - p.335 Chapter XXXIX (Sawdust Diet) (15.53 [P.B.3])
    - p.263 Chapter XXX (The Duke Went for Him) (15.54 [P.B.3])
    - p.314 Chapter XXVI (Tom Advises A Witch Pie) (15.54 [P.B.3])
    - p.266 Chapter XXI (Spanish Moss) (15.55 [P.B.3])
    - p.277 Chapter XXXII (Still and Sunday Like) (15.55 [P.B.3])
    - p.271 Chapter XXXI (Thinking) (15.56 [P.B.3])
    - p.275 Striking For the Back Country (15.56 [P.B.3])
    - p.271 He Gave Him Ten Cents (15.57 [P.B.3])
    - p.307 Chapter XXV (Smouching the Knives) (15.57 [P.B.3])
    - p.279 Chapter XXXII (She Hugged Him Tight) (15.58 [P.B.3])
    - p.284 Chapter XXXIIII ("It Was Tom Sawyer") (15.58 [P.B.3])
    - p.287 Chapter XXXIII ("Mr.Archibald Nichols, I Presume?") (15.59 [P.B.3])
    - p.291 Traveling by Rail (15.59 [P.B.3])
    - p.299 Chapter XXXIV (Witches) (15.59 [P.B.3])
    - p.296 A Simple Job (15.60 [P.B.3])
    - p.327 Chapter XXXVIII (A Tough Job) (15.60 [P.B.3])
    - p.300 Chapter XXV (Getting Wood) (15.61 [P.B.3])
    - p.293 Chapter XXXIV (Vittles) (15.61 [P.B.3])
    - p.309 Chapter XXVI (Going Down the Lightning-Rod) (15.62 [P.B.3])
    - p.364 Chapter the Last (Out of Bondage) (15.62 [P.B.3])
    - p.311 Chapter XXXVI (Stealing Spoons) (15.63 [P.B.3])
    - p.329 Chapter XXXVIII (Buttons on Their Tails) (15.63 [P.B.3])
    - p.316 Chapter XXXVII (The Rubbage-Pile) (15.64 [P.B.3])
    - p.347 Chapter XLI (The Doctor) (15.64 [P.B.3])
    - p.318 Chapter XXXVII ("Missus, Dey's A Sheet Gone") (15.65 [P.B.3])
    - p.260 Chapter XXIX ("Jim Let Out") (15.65 [P.B.3])
    - p.321 Chapter XXXVII (In A Tearing Way) (15.66 [P.B.3])
    - p.290 Chapter XXXIII (A Pretty Long Blessing) (15.66 [P.B.3])
    - p.322 Chapter XXXVII (One of His Ancestors) (15.67 [P.B.3])